# **VLADISLAV KIBAKOV**

+491706590903 vladislav.kibakov@gmail.com vladislav-kibakov.github.io Königsbronn, Germany

Automation & Controls Engineer with 6 years' experience in the maintenance of industrial automation systems and developing/implementing new ones as commercial projects. In-depth knowledge of PLC / HMI / SCADA (DCS) programming. Able to work with automation devices from many manufacturers. Looking to fill a position of a plant Automation & Controls Engineer, but ready to consider other options.

## **Experience**

#### **Engineering Consultant**

PIXIDA GmbH Aug 2022 - Present, Germany

- Part of PLC development team for Zeiss SMT facility (Oberkochen). The facility produces Extreme Ultraviolet Lithography Optics for the unique in the whole world process of manufacturing microchips with EUV technology by the ASML company
- Responsible for PLC/HMI software development and support in HRTP project for 3 robot cells modules. Robots move mounts with EUV Lithography Optics between stations. The process considers precision and risk of high-cost material damage
- Finished intensive 8-week onboarding training with developing and presenting own fully functional project
- The software development through a strictly controlled procedure. In 4 months 19 software releases of different scale from bugfixes to new features implementation that increased production performance or improved human safety
- Work in a clean room environment

#### **Senior Programming Engineer**

Kazcentrnaladka / TechnoAutomatica LLP Oct 2017 - Aug 2022, Kazakhstan

- Ensured troubleproof operation of automation equipment of enrichment plant of the largest copper producer in Kazakhstan — Kazakhmys Corporation LLC. The production rate of the plant was processing 3,500,000 tons of copper ore per year. Continuous production
- Managed 37 PLCs, 13 HMIs, 2 SCADA servers, 3000 D(I/O) / A(I/O) signals as the only PLC Programmer on the plant. This includes troubleshooting, editing code or writing projects from scratch
- Implemented 4 commercial projects worth from 4000\$ up to 75000\$ in mining and manufacturing industries. Also made on my initiative modernizations projects free of costs by using existing or unused equipment to increase trouble-free uptime or production rate of the plant. For details visit my website vladislav-kibakov.github.io
- Automated new technological equipment and integrated it into the existing automation system. Such as new pumps, compressors, conveyors

#### **Junior Automation Engineer** KAZCENTRELECTROPROVOD LLP Aug 2016 - Oct 2017, Kazakhstan

- Ensured troubleproof operation of automation equipment of the cable production factory. This includes sensors, regulators, VFDs, PLCs, HMIs, SCADAs. The scale of the factory is 20 cable production lines, 26 "Twisting in a pair" machines, and additional units, such as press and rewinding machines
- Edited the program code of PLC / HMI / SCADA
- Implemented measurement and display of the length of the produced cable and linear speed on 2 old cable production lines

## **Skills**

### Non-technical skills:

- Teamwork and communication skills
- · Ability to work independently
- Self-study, ability to learn new technologies | VFDs Mitsubishi, Yaskawa, Delta
- workflow

#### Technical skills:

- PLC / HMI / SCADA (DCS) programming Mitsubishi, Siemens, Delta
- Industrial Networks Profibus, CC link IE, Modbus RTU/TCP, OPC DA/UA
- Self-motivation and a desire to improve the Projects research, design, installation, programming, commissioning
  - Python / Databases completed courses

## **Education**

#### **Master of Engineering and Technology** in Automation and Control

Karaganda State Technical University, 2016–2018

Bachelor of Engineering and **Technology in Electric Power Engineering** 

Karaganda State Technical University, 2012–2016

Educational program — Robotics & Control systems GPA — 3.72/4.0

The diploma is accredited by World Education Services

Educational program — Electric drive and automation of mining technological complexes

GPA — 3.72/4.0

The diploma is accredited by World Education Services

# Languages

**English**: IELTS 7.5/9 (CEFR — C1)

Russian: Native

# Interests

Training, Soccer, Pro-Wrestling, Video Games, Books